A Guide to the Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, 1862-1863
Virginia Military Institute Archives
Archives, Preston Library, Virginia Military Institute
Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers 1862-1863
Archives, Preston Library, Virginia Military Institute
mss 00361
The collection contains 17 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Alternative Form
The Langhorne Papers are available in full-text format on the VMI Archives website at: http://www.vmi.edu/archives/manuscripts/ms361.html
Biographical/Historical Information
Jacob Kent Langhorne ("Kent") was born in Montgomery County, Virginia, on March 1, 1845. He matriculated at the Virginia Military Institute in August 1862 and left VMI in February 1863 to join the Confederate Army. Langhorne enlisted in Company C, 2nd Virginia Cavalry Regiment and was killed in battle at Brandy Station on June 9, 1863. He is buried in the Crockett-Kent graveyard near Shawsville, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist of 17 Civil War letters (Sept 1862-May 1863) from Jacob Kent Langhorne to various members of his family, written during his Virginia Military Institute cadetship and his service in the Confederate Army with the 2nd Virginia Cavalry Regiment. Topics include cadet life, family matters, camp life.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Virginia Military Institute Correspondence 1862
  This series contains 10 letters written by Langhorne to his family while he was a cadet at the Virginia Military Institute in Lexington, Virginia. Topics include cadets life and family matters.
  - 1862 September 1
  - 1862 September 13
  - 1862 September 28
  - 1862 October 5
  - 1862 October 20
  - 1862 November 2
  - 1862 November 10
  - 1862 November 16
  - 1862 November 23
  - 1862 December 20
- Civil War Service Correspondence 1863
  This series contains 7 letters written by Langhorne while he was servicing with the 2nd Virginia Cavalry Regiment. Topics include camp life, family news.
  - 1863 January 2
  - 1863 May 4
  - 1863 May 8
  - 1863 May 11
  - 1863 May 18
  - 1863 May 19, with enclosure
  - 1863 June 1